DALLAN JONES

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a full-stack web developer with an extensive background in computers and programming. I am able to build complex back-end applications while maintaining a friendly user experience.

I have been studying on my own as well as attending Juno College for front-end development and Brock University for computer science

CONTACT INFORMATION

Cell: 905-380-8445 contact@dallan.ca www.dallan.ca <u>www.github.com/dallanj</u> www.linkedin.com/in/dallanj

Based in Mississauga, ON, Canada

EDUCATION

Juno College 2021

- Web Development Immersive Bootcamp
- Con ED JavaScript Course

Brock University 2016-2021

- Computer Science 2 Years
- Business Economics 1 Year

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- PHP, SQL, Laravel, Livewire, Tailwind, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Linux, Sass, Networking,
- Advanced programming fundamentals
- OOP PHP following MVC structure
- Utilizing external libraries and frameworks
- Accessibility, UX and UI

TOP PROJECTS

Relay Chat

A secure encrypted live chat platform

- Built using; PHP, SQL, jQuery, PGP software, HTML & CSS
- The backend was built using OOP PHP following an MVC structure
- Used asynchronous AJAX calls to PHP scripts to manipulate the DOM
- Used PGP encryption for messages between users and hashed each user's password within the MySQL database

Sun Run

An app that utilizes Location IQ and Sunrise/Sunset APIs as well as being connected to a firebase database

- Built using React, Firebase, HTML & CSS
- Used multiple APIs and integrated firebase to hold unique user IDs
- Created a sleek and user friendly interface with accessibility
- Worked within a group of students and utilizing Git

EMPLOYMENT & EXPERIENCE

Mentorship Program

Juno College of Technology. (2022 - Present)

- Mentoring students one on one on a regular basis, assisting with web development and technologies like JavaScript, React, Git, Firebase, HTML + CSS, Sass and more
- Answer questions, help debug and refactor student's code toward a solution. All while still keeping user experience, accessibility and ease of use in mind

Junior Full-Stack Developer

PDERAS Consulting. (2022 - Present)

- Using PHP, Laravel, JavaScript Vue.js/Vuex, MySQL, as a primary tech stack
- Using Tailwind, Sass and Bootstrap as CSS frameworks
- Performing complex front and back end tasks on large scale
- Utilizing Git version control within a team setting
- Using Mac OS as a desktop environment
- Collaborating with team members in a different time zone through a remote setting